詹森 · 兰斯托夫: 启动器里面有一些东西，所以
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: The starter
has a few things in it so
我们不需要从头开始编写所有的代码
that we don't have to write all
of the code from scratch, but for
第一部分，我们要设计一个主题。
this first part,
we're gonna be developing a theme.
为了发展《了不起的盖茨比》的主题，我们需要一个叫做纱线工作区的东西。
And to develop themes in Gatsby,
we need something called yarn workspaces.
所以纱线工作空间是我们能够
So a yarn workspace is
a way that we are able to
同时处理两个包裹。
work on two packages simultaneously.
通常来说，如果你在一个网站上工作，如果你想使用一个软件包,
So typically speaking, if you're working
on a site if you wanna use a package,
你将纱线安装包装名称，它进入您的包 JSON 和
you would yarn install the package name
and it goes into your package JSON and and
然后你就可以继续努力了。
then you can work on it.
但如果你想改变一下包装,
But if you wanna make
a change to that package,
然后你就必须把它发布到 NPM。
then you would have to publish it to NPM.
然后最迟重新安装它以获得这些更改。
And then reinstall it at
latest to get those changes.
这真的很麻烦，我们不想这么做，对吧？
And that's really cumbersome and
we just don't wanna do that, right?
所以纱线工作区让我们做的是，它让我们钩住一个本地文件夹作为
So what yarn workspaces will let us do
is it lets us hook up a local folder as
包裹。
a package.
所以一旦你建立了纱线工作区,
So once you've got yarn workspaces set up,
我们可以设置我们的主题作为一个包裹，我们可以纱线安装。
we can set our theme as a package
that we can yarn install.
但是如果我们做局部修改，它就会被选中
But it will do it in a way that if we make
local modifications that will get picked
就在我们正在开发的地方。
up by the site that we're developing with.
这一点很重要，因为《了不起的盖茨比》的主题被设计成
And that's important because
Gatsby themes are designed to take
配置选项。
configuration options.
这意味着它们不能独立运行。
And that means that they
don't run standalone.
为了正常运行，它们必须由另一个站点安装。
They have to be installed by another
site in order to function properly.
所以，我们首先要做的是
So, what we're gonna do first is we
将为主题创建一个文件夹。
are going to create a folder for
the theme.
所以我通常称之为软件包，因为它不是
So I typically call this packages
because it's something that wouldn't be
完成最高水平。
done top level.
你想怎么叫都行,
You can call it whatever you want,
这里没有什么严格的变数命名原则。
there's not a hard and
fast naming convention here.
这只是我学到的，你可以做任何你想做的事情。
This is just what I picked up,
you're welcome to do whatever you like.
然后我会用包的名字。
And then I'm gonna use
the name of the package.
所以我们来做盖茨比主题文档。
So we'll do gatsby-theme-docs.
在这里面，我要打开我的终端，进入它。
And inside of this, I'm gonna open
up my terminal and get into it.
我们来看包裹吧，盖茨比主题文档。
Let's go into packages, gatsby-theme-docs.
然后我要在里面运行纱线。
And then I'm going to run yarn init.
它会问我们一些问题。
And what this will do is it's
gonna ask us some questions.
所以名字是的，我想成为盖茨比主题的博士。
So the name yes,
I wanted to be gatsby-themed-docs.
记住这一点很重要，因为
And it's important to
remember that because that is
我们要用的东西。
what we're gonna have to use.
喜欢我们将做纱线工作空间和名称的包装。
Like we will do yarn workspace and
the name of the package.
还有一个关于盖茨比主题的重要提示,
And an important note about Gatsby themes,
《了不起的盖茨比》开头的主题很重要。
the Gatsby theme at
the beginning is important.
你必须把你的主题命名为盖茨比破折号主题。
You have to name your theme
with Gatsby dash theme.
这是我们如何工作的阴影算法的一部分。
That's part of how we work
the shadowing algorithm.
所以当你建立一个自定义主题时，你总是需要使用盖茨比主题。
So when you're building a custom theme,
you always need to use Gatsby theme.
然后我们可以保持版本默认，我们不需要一个说明。
Then we can keep the version default
we don't need a description.
Js 入口点很好。
The index.js entry point is fine.
我们将跳过使用默认值，好吗？
We'll skip that use default, okay?
所以一旦我们有了这个，当我们看到我们的包装 Jason,
So once we have that,
when we look into our package Jason,
我们可以看到这里有主题文档。
we can see here that
we've got the theme docs.
这就是我们工作区的名字。
And that's gonna be
the name of our workspace.
为了建立工作空间我们要走主题路线,
So to set up work spaces we're
gonna go out to the theme route,
我们要做一个包装 json。
and we're going to create a package.json.
这个和一般的有点不同。
And this one's a little
different from the average one.
首先我们要把它设置为 private 因为它必须是 private
So first we're gonna set it to private
because it has to be private in order for
工作空间的功能。
workspaces to function.
你不能发布一个工作空间。
You can't publish a workspace.
然后我们要设置工作区，这是一个数组。
Then we're gonna set up workspaces,
which is an array.
我们把这个设置成从两个文件夹读取。
And we're gonna set this up
to read from two folders.
第一个是包裹文件夹
The first one is gonna be
the packages folder because we
希望能够使用我们刚才创建的主题。
wanna be able to use that
theme that we just created.
第二个是网站的文件夹。
And the second one is the site's folder.
我们这里有很多网站。
So we've got a bunch of sites in here.
所以我们要在网站里面说点什么,
So we're gonna say
anything inside of sites,
你也应该把它当作一个工作区。
you should also read as a workspace.
一旦我们在这里，然后我可以做纱线工作区信息。
Once we're in here,
then I can do yarn workspaces info.
它将向我们展示的是，这些网站以一个包的形式出现。
And what it'll show us is each of
these sites shows up as a package.
它会告诉我们它住在哪里。
It’ll show us where it lives.
然后，它会告诉我们是否有任何工作区依赖项。
Then, it’ll show us if we have
any workspace dependencies.
我们可以在这里看到开头,
We can see here at the beginning,
这些网站都没有工作空间依赖性。
none of these sites have
any workspace dependencies.
这个可以但我们不用担心这个,
Now, this one does, but
we’re not gonna worry about that,
因为这和我们今天的工作无关。
because it’s not really relevant
to what we’re doing today.
然后我们准备了盖茨比主题的文档，在这里布置得恰到好处。
And then we've got our gatsby-themed-docs,
which is set up in here properly.
所以我们需要弄清楚的是
So what we do need to figure out though,
is one thing that's
重要的是要了解包是包依赖于这一点
important to know about packages
is that packages rely on this
主文件夹来确定包是否存在。
main folder to determine whether or
not the package exists.
因此，当您安装一个软件包时，如果您尝试使用它，那么该节点将首先
So when you install a package if you try
to use it, the first thing that node will
它会调查这个名字，并确保文件的存在
do is it'll look into that name and make
sure that whatever the file is exists, and
如果没有，它就会说包裹无效。
if it doesn't,
it'll say that the package is invalid.
所以我们实际上不会使用一个索引 js。
So we're not actually
gonna use an index js.
所以我们要创建它，然后做一个小笔记
So we're just gonna create it and
then make a little note so
人们知道这是为了。
that people know that this is intended.
这有点像这页故意留下空白的东西。
It's kind of like this page
intentionally left blank sort of thing.
你想放什么都可以。
You can put whatever you want in there.
我的嘘声是我标准的愚蠢评论。
I boop is like my standard silly comment.
一旦设置好了，现在我们可以设置主题开发站点了。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Once this is set up,
now we can set up the theme dev site.
所以我们要在我们网站的文件夹里创建一个全新的网站,
So we're just gonna create a whole
new site inside of our site's folder,
我们称之为主题开发。
we'll call it theme-dev.
再说一次，我们要打开终端,
And again,
we're gonna pull up the terminal,
进入，Jason Lengstorf: sites / theme-dev 和
go into the,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Sites/theme-dev and
然后我们再编一次。
then we will yarn init again.
这次我们将保留主题的名称-dev，保留版本,
And this time we'll keep the name
theme-dev, keep the version,
描述，所有可能保持不变。
description, all that can stay the same.
但我要把二等兵设为真因为
But what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna set
the private on this one to true because
一般来说，你不会想把一个网站打包发布在 npm net 上。
typically speaking, you don't wanna
publish a website as a package on npm net.
你可以这么做，但是这么做并没有什么好的理由。
You could, but there's not
really a good reason to do that.
所以在这里，我们要有我们的 JSON 和
So then in here,
we're gonna have our package JSON and
设置为隐私，这样我们就不会不小心发表了。
it's set to private so
that we don't accidentally publish it.
在这里，我现在可以添加一些东西。
In this, I can now add a few things.
最后还是有一点点不同。
In the end there's a small difference.
通常当你添加纱或 NPM 的筒子，你做 NPM 安装或纱添加。
Typically when you add packages in yarn or
NPM, you do NPM install or yarn add.
所以对于工作空间,
So with workspaces,
我们只要在广告前面加上，我们想用的工作区的名字。
we just prefix the ad with the name
of the workspace we wanna use.
所以我要说纱线工作空间主题-开发，然后我要添加。
So I'm gonna say yarn workspace
theme-dev and then I'm gonna add.
现在，我可以随心所欲地添加任何东西。
And now, I can just add whatever I want.
所以我要做盖茨比的反应和反应-唐。
So I'll do gatsby react and react-dom.
我们就在这里检查一下，这个可以做我们想做的事情。
And we'll just check out in here
that this is gonna do what we want.
所以它正在安装 Jason Lengstorf: 好的，好的,
So it's installing
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay all right,
所以结果和我们预期的一样。
so it showed up the way we expected.
现在我们要做的就是安装我们的主题。
So now what we wanna do is
we wanna install our theme.
纱线工作区主题-开发添加，和
yarn workspace theme-dev add, and
然后在 Windows 和 SeaShell 上引用。
then to quote it out for
Windows and SeaShell.
我们说 gatsby-theme-docs@* 和@* 就是指这个节点
We'll say gatsby-theme-docs @* and
@* just means that node
都不会介意这不是一个公开的包裹。
will be okay with the fact that
it's not a published package.
所以，一旦我们得到了它，我们就会看到它弹出在我们的 JSON 包中。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So once we get that,
we'll see it pop up in our package JSON.
开始了。
And here we go.
所以现在如果我再次运行纱线工作区信息。
So now if I run yarn
workspaces info again.
这里应该是入口。
And this is where it should be portal.
然后我可以看看我们的主题-dev,
Then I can see if I look at our theme-dev,
现在我们有了工作空间的依赖关系。
now we've got workspace
dependencies in here.
这意味着盖茨比主题文档被当作
And what this means is that
gatsby-theme-docs is being treated as
它的工作原理与从 NPM 安装的软件包完全相同。
a package it will work exactly the same
as a package installed from NPM.
但是现在的好处是它使用了本地文件。
But the benefit now is that
it's using local file.
所以当我修改这个盖茨比主题的文档文件夹时
So when I make changes to this
gatsby-themed-docs folder up
这里是左上角,
here in the top left,
这将反映在主题开发网站，好像它是从 NPM 下载的。
that will reflect in the theme-dev site
as if it were downloaded from NPM.
所以，接下来我们要进入我们的主题-开发和
So, next we're going to
get into our theme-dev and
我们要安装这个主题。
we're going to install this theme.
因此，让我们继续前进，创建一个 gatsby-config. js。
So let's just go ahead and
create a gatsby-config.js.
这里将成为任何一个标准的盖茨比遗址的中心。
This is gonna be kind of the heart
of any standard Gatsby site.
让我把这个放下来一点
So let me drop this down a little bit and
我们说模块，出口和
we'll say module.exports and
这将是一个配置对象。
that's going to be a config object.
在这里面我们会有一个插件数组。
And inside of this we're
gonna have a plug-ins array.
如果你想把所有的主题都用上，你在《了不起的盖茨比》中默认安装主题的方式
And the way that you install a theme in
Gatsby by default, if you wanna use all
默认的选项和所有的东西，就是你可以把它放在那里。
the default options and everything,
is you can just drop it right in there.
所以我们要说”盖茨比主题”如果我能拼出来的话”盖茨比主题文件”。
So we're gonna say gatsby-theme,
if I can spell it, gatsby-theme-docs.
在保存这个主题之后，我们现在正在有效地使用这个主题。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And upon saving this,
we are now effectively using this theme.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 它现在不会做任何事情，但是
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
it won't do anything right now, but
如果我启动它就不会爆炸。
it won't explode if I start it.
所以我要来这里，我要添加一些脚本，所以
So I'm going to come in here, and
I'm just gonna add some scripts so
我们可以从命令行开始。
that we can start Gatsby
from the command line.
因此，让我们添加一个脚本键。
So let's add a scripts key.
我们将投入开发，我们的开发指令将是《盖茨比开发》。
And we'll put in develop, and our develop
command is gonna be gatsby develop.
现在，我应该能够做的是，这是一个空的网站,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So now, what I should
be able to do, and this is an empty site,
所以我们只能得到404。
so it's just gonna give us a 404.
但我可以做纱线工作空间主题开发。
But I can do yarn workspace
theme-dev develop.
这应该就是我们的盖茨比基地了
And this should start our gatsby site
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好了，我们开始
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay, so we're up and
我们现在可以看到它的存在，所以如果我切换到这里。
running and we can see now that it
exists so if I switch out to here.
然后打开我们看到盖茨比正在运行的页面，我们没有任何内容
And run the page we can see that Gatsby
is running, we don't have any content or
但是它所做的正是我们所期望的，它实际上是在加载页面。
anything in herebBut it's doing what we
expect it is actually loading the page.
所以这让我们处于一个我们想要的位置,
So that puts us in a position
that we wanna be in,
就是我们可以开始在网站上开发。
which is that we can start
actually developing on the site.
这是一个工作空间。
So this is kind of
the workspace is set up.
这就是你的任何主题开发，这是你要开始
That's that's where you for any theme-dev,
this is where you're gonna wanna start
基本上就是杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 那么让我们继续
basically
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So let's go ahead and
承认吧。
commit that.
我要去看看新开的分店。
I'm gonna check out a new branch.
所以我们要做 git 检查分行。
So we'll do git check out branch.
我们称之为费尔南大师的进步。
And we'll call this
fernan masters progress.
我要检查 git 的状态，Jason Lengstorf: 好的,
And I'm going to check git status,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay,
我要把所有东西都加进去。
and I'm just gonna add everything.
Jason Lengstorf: 这个显示在我们的队列中
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: This
shows is in our queue and
我们有一包工作用的杰森,
we've got a pack of json which is for
work spaces,
然后是盖茨比主题，索引上的包裹。
then we've got our gatsby-theme-docs
the packages on the index.
主题开发站点的 gatsby-config 和 package.json，然后是 yarn.lock,
The gatsby-config and the package.json for
the theme dev site, and then a yarn.lock,
这只是跟踪依赖关系。
which is just tracking dependencies.
所以我要继续前进，承诺这一点。
So I'm going to go ahead and commit that.
我会使用传统的提交。
And I'm gonna use conventional commits.
因此，我们将说主题开发，Jason Lengstorf: Workspace setup。
So we'll say theme-dev,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Workspace setup.